(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T08:33:36.931373",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
LETTER☆彡 Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Celebration 2023
[Title: LETTER☆彡 Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Celebration 2023]
2023.10.5
Fubuki Shirakami Birthday Live
HAPPY BIRTHDAY
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD,
アイノウ 僕らのTRUEな世界
I know it's our TRUE world!
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD,
アイノウ 僕らのTRUEな世界
I know it's our TRUE world!
混沌とワンダーランド 電脳とアンバランス
Chaos and wonderland, computer and unbalance,
あふれそうだ大変 でも日常もWe go on!
overflowing and in a panic, but every day is we go on!
コンニチハ・バーチャライズ 退屈はカスタマイズ
Konnichiwa, Virtualize! Boredom is customize,
楽しくなりそうだ! ワナビー これでスタンバイ!
this is gonna be so fun! Wanna be ready for standby!
「世界制覇? 頂上か実力か」「シロかクロか」「アタマかカラダか」
"World domination? Top or ability?" "Top or bottom? White or black?" "Head or body?"
ミーアイヤ シッポを忘れちゃいけないね!
Hey, don't forget your dreams and tail!
スキキライもエモビもなんでもいいんだ キミと一緒の世界なら
Likes, dislikes, emotional, beautiful, anything goes in our shared world!
はじめよう 僕らのKINGWORLD
Let's start, our KINGWORLD!
アイノウ 僕らのTRUEな世界
I know it's our TRUE world!
フリもムキも全部全部詰め込んで!
Fruits, mood, everything stuffed inside!
サドデスにカタカタなモンスター 愛追う気まぐれなトリックスター
Sudden, shaky monster, love-struck, fickle trickster,
「誰のこと?」なんて言うもんか! ようこそ 僕らのKINGWORLD
Who cares whose it is? Welcome to our KINGWORLD!
新世界シンドローム 妄想徒レジスタンス
New world syndrome, delusion resistance,
クラクラしてないかい? 理論武装 過熱オーバーヒート!
aren't you getting dizzy? Theorized and overheated!
白熱のハートビート 上等さSnowstorm
Torrid heartbeat, top-tier snowstorm,
せわしくなりそうだ! 戦場は猛コンジェッション
this is gonna be so fun, the battlefield is congested!
出会い 別れ変わりゆく世界で どれだけキミを守ってゆけるのだろう
In a changing world of meetings and partings, how much can I protect you?
電脳とアンバランス あふれそうだ大変!
Computer and unbalance, overflowing and in a panic!
コンニチハ・バーチャライズ 退屈はカスタマイズ
Konnichiwa, Virtualize! Boredom is customize,
繰り返す日々 増えるプレイヤー どれだけのキミを守ってこれたのだろう
repeating days, increasing players, how much can I protect you?
吹き荒れる世界が変わってしまっても キミはまだキミでいてくれるかい 続けよう
Even if this raging world changes, you're still you—keep on going,
僕らのKINGWORLD
Our KINGWORLD!
アイノウ 僕らのTRUEな世界
I know it's our TRUE world!
傷だらけのシッポで今日モ今日モ打ち鳴らせ
With a scarred tail, let's make today roar!
空回りメルヘなジョーカー 妄想で暴走超ハンター
Spinning, ridiculous fairy-tale joker, delusional runaway hunter,
「誰のこと?」なんて言わないね! ようこそ 僕らのKINGWORLD
who cares whose it is? Welcome to our KINGWORLD!
ホンネをいっちゃおう タテマエもホンネもセイギもギセイも
Saying what you really think, rights and wrongs, justice and vice,
ニガテだ 平和がイチバンじゃないかネ!
aren't you tired of it? Isn't peace the best?
でもでもでも ファイヤクライヤーチモリョウ なんでもこいやだ!
No matter what, fire, cryer, demons, spirits, anything goes,
キミと生きてく世界なら
in a world where I live with you!
アーユーレディ 僕らのKINGWORLD アイノウ 僕らのTRUEな世界
Are you ready? Our KINGWORLD, I know it's our TRUE world!
キミもキミもエモもビも 全部全部詰め込んで!
Likes, dislikes, emotional, beautiful, everything stuffed inside!
壮絶なアノマリーからクリックザハート 怨鬼に触れたらセイヴザライフ
A magnificent anomaly, click the heart, touch the demon and seize the day!
誰でもきっと叫ぶだろう ようこそ…
Whatever it is, you're sure to shout out: Welcome...
終わらない僕らのKINGWORLD そう願う僕のTRUEな世界
to our never-ending KINGWORLD! So prays my TRUE world!
夢もキズも全部全部詰め込んで!
Dreams and scars, everything, everything stuffed inside!
電脳王様はまだ夢の中
The cyber king is still deep in a dream.
アイノウ 混沌とワンダーランド ゆこうその先の先の先の
Ai-ou, chaos and wonderland, follow beyond that!
ようこそ 僕らのKINGWORLD
Welcome to our KINGWORLD!
インターネット・エンジェルという現象は
The phenomenon known as Internet Angel
仮定された有機交流電燈の
is a hypothesized organic alternating-current electric lamp's
かわいい虹色の照明です ほいっ
cute rainbow-colored illumination! Hui!
あらゆる透明なアカウントの複合体
This complex of every transparent account,
このクソゴミカシキシキシな現実を忘れさせてあげる慈愛の天使
makes us forget this crappy, cringe reality as an angel of charity!
大人のみんなにはナイショだぞ
Keep it a secret from all the adults, okay?
大丈夫 もうなにも怖くないからこういうSNS抜け出して二人で海を見に行くぞ!
Don't worry, you won't be scared anymore, so let's sneak out of this SNS and go see the ocean together!
インターネットやめろ!
INTERNET YAMERO!
わかる真似をしてなににも知らないねアナタ
Pretending to understand, you know nothing at all, do you?
わかる真似をして なにも知らないね
You pretend to understand, but you know nothing
アナタ
at all, you.
なにが悲しいの
What is sadness, really?
なにが寂しいの
What is loneliness?
聴こえてる？
Are you listening?
人が恋しくて
People are longing for people,
人がイヤすぎて
yet people are too annoying—
ループ
a loop.
夜が好きなのに
Even though I love the night,
一人じゃ寒くて 震えてる
I'm all alone, cold, and shivering.
ほんとうは幸せを知っているのに
Even though I truly know what happiness is,
不幸なフリやめられないね
I just can't stop playing the victim.
アンチに負けず信者に媚びず どんなに努力を重ねても
Never yielding to haters, never pandering to zealots, no matter how hard I work,
一寸先は地獄行き いやもうすでに冥府魔道
One inch ahead is hell—no, I'm already walking the underworld's demonic path.
地獄の沙汰もいいね次第 偽善者トラップ 蜘蛛の糸
Judgment in hell depends on likes; hypocrite's trap, spider's thread.
こんなに苦しいはずなのに
Even though it hurts so much,
インターネットがやめられないない！
I just can't quit the internet!
かけめぐる エクスタシー 溶ける マイスリー
Running through my body is ecstasy, melting is myslee,
画面光りだすの 不安止まらないよ
My screen starts to light up, and the anxiety won't stop.
誰か殺してくれ イヤだ 死にたくない
Someone, please kill me! No, I don't want to die!
朝は見いたくないの ムリだ 死ぬ！
I don't want to see the morning! No way, I'm dying!
頭が割れてく！
My head is splitting open!
それでもわたしはこのカオスをオタクと歩む
Even so, I will walk through this chaos with my nerds.
ここにしかない光景を見つけに行くから
I'm going to find the scenery that can only be found here.
あんなにおそろしい乱れたインターネットから
From that terrifying, distorted internet,
この雪みたいに美しい毒電波がきたんだよ
came this poison radio wave as beautiful as snow.
カウンセリングを受けたの
I went to get a therapist,
先生から「ネットをやめろ」って言われて
and they told me to "get off the internet."
もうお前らと会えないと思った瞬間胸が苦しくて
But the moment I thought I'd never see you guys again, my chest ached so much—
リアルは壊れてもここが良いって思ったの
I thought, even if the real world breaks, this place is fine.
初めてフォローされた日のこと覚えてる？
Do you remember the day you first followed me?
こんなわたしを見て承認してくれた温もりで
With the warmth of someone looking at me like this and validating me,
もう細かいことはどうでもいいね
I don't care about the little things anymore!
せーの インターネット最高！！！
Ready, set—Internet is the best!!!
キボンヌ！オワタ！半年ROMれ！キター！age！漏れ！香具師！逝ってよし！久々にワロタ！
Kibonnu! Owata! ROM for half a year! Kita! Age! More! Kaushi! Itte yoshi! Long time no lol!
これは乙じゃなくてポニョテールなんだからね！フヒヒ！ぬるぽ！蕣同！
This isn't ozu, it's a pony-tail, you know! Fuhihi! Nurupo! Shundo!
無理ぽ！オマエモナー！お礼は三行！うpぽい！日本語でおk！>>1の母です！(久々にワロタ！)
Muripo! Omaemona! Thanks in three lines! Uppo! Japanese please! I'm >>1's mother! (Long time no lol!)
キボンヌ！オワタ！半年ROMれ！キター！age！漏れ！香具師！逝ってよし！
Kibonnu! Owata! ROM for half a year! Kita! Age! More! Kaushi! Itte yoshi!
久々にワロタ！
Long time no lol!
フヒヒ！
Fuhihi!
青白いモニター越しの光を通し オタクの孤独を癒して回る
Passing through the light beyond the pale monitor, I go around healing the loneliness of all nerds.
わたしはインターネットの天使なのだ
For I am the internet angel.
はーい、ということでみなさん、こんばんはー！
Hii, so everyone, good evening!
あ、ありがとうと言いますか、ふわふわシッポのご奉仕、
Ah, thank you so much—fluffy tail service,
あなたの心のいちばんの……あ、恥ずかしい、
right in the center of your heart... ah, how embarrassing!
白上フブキでーす！わーい！
I'm Shirakami Fubuki! Yay!
えー、本日はですね、白上フブキ生誕祭2023サブタイトルに、お越し下さりありがとうございます！
Um, today, thank you so much for coming to the Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Party 2023 with subtitle!
わーい！わいわいわい！
Yay! Yay! Yay!
えー、やばい、もう最初から結構疲れちゃってんですけども、
Uh, oh no, I'm already pretty exhausted right from the start, but—
えー、まずは「キングワールド」と、そして「インターネットヤメロ」聴いていただきましたー！
uh, first we listened to "King World" and also "Internet Yamero"!
いや、「キングワールド」ね、もうしょっぱから噛みそうに、え、なる曲なんですけども、ダンスもいい感じに踊れたんじゃないでしょうか！
Man, "King World" is a song where I almost tripped over my tongue right from the start, but I think I danced pretty well, don't you think?
そして、「インターネットヤメロ」、やめろやめろやめろー！
And "Internet Yamero"—stop, stop, stop!
え、やめられないんですよね、なんでもないインターネットは、こちらもね、ちょっとダンス踊らせていただきました！めちゃめちゃ楽しかったですー！
Uh, I can't quit it, you know—harmless internet. I got to dance to this one too! It was super fun!
そして、そんな今日のですね、ハッシュタグ上にございます、白上フブキ生誕祭2023で、
And, for today's hashtag on screen, "Shirakami Fubuki Birthday Party 2023",
いっぱいスクショしてくれると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！わーい！
I'd be so happy if you take lots of screenshots! Please check it out! Yay!
さて、ではですね、今日は完全ソロライブということで、もうね、歌ったり踊ったりフリーなダンスしちゃったり、楽しんでいこうと思いますので皆さんもいっぱい楽しんでいってください！
Now then, today is a completely solo live, so singing, dancing, doing freeform dances—we're going to have a lot of fun, so I hope you all enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
では、早速次の曲に行く前にちょっとね、お水も……
Now, before we head right into the next song, let's get some water...
お、えー、飲みつつで行こうと思いますが、えー、
Um, well, I thought I'd keep drinking as I go, but um...
ちょっとお水飲むか、いっしょか。
Should I drink some water? Together, huh.
はい、はいお邪魔しました。
Yep, yep, sorry for interrupting!
では、次の曲いきましょう。
Now then, let's move on to the next song.
次の曲は、皆さん、もちろんこれとかも覚えてますよね？
For the next song, of course everyone remembers this, right?
Hi Fine FOXです！いっぱいサイリウムも振ってね！
It's Hi Fine FOX!! Wave your glow sticks lots!
こんこんきーつね！
Kon-kon-kitsune!
私は白上フブキです！
I'm Shirakami Fubuki!
お歌とお茶とゲームが大好き、オタクなバーチャル狐です！
I love singing, tea, and games! A nerdy virtual fox!
いろんなことして毎日楽しく活動してるので、
Doing all sorts of things and having fun every day,
ふぶちゃん、フブキ、白上、皆さんお好きに呼んでください！
Fubu-chan, Fubuki, Shirakami—please call me whatever you like!
Hi friends! 今日がはじめてのひとも
Hi friends! To those here for the first time,
Hi friends! いつも見くれてるひとも
Hi friends! To those who always watch,
Hi friends! 一人一人のチカラで
Hi friends! With everyone's individual power,
Hi friends! 私はここにいます
Hi friends! I am right here.
そう 今も ずっと
Yes, now and forever
変わらないこの場所で
in this unchanging place,
キミといつでも推したって Welcome friends!
supporting you anytime, Welcome friends!
まだまだ道の途中
We're still along the way.
慌ただしく過ぎる日々は宝物だよ
Days passing in a rush are treasures!
泣いたってしょげたって大丈夫じゃい！
Even if you cry or feel down, it's alright!
笑顔で一緒にHi Fine FOX!!
Together with a smile, Hi Fine FOX!!
ココロを歌に重ねて
Layering our hearts into song,
届けましょうMy Happy Days
let's deliver them, My Happy Days!
はーじまっぼーう！今日は何をして遊びましょうか？
Let's start! What shall we play today?
お茶でも飲んでひと息ーってもうこんな時間！？
Drinking tea and taking a breath—wait, it's already this late!?
皆さんのことももっと知れたら私も幸せなので！
Getting to know everyone more makes me happy too!
釣ったり狩ったりアピールしたり皆さんせーのでご一緒に！
Fishing, hunting, appealing—everyone, ready, together!
Hi friends! 楽しくて飛び跳ねる日も
Hi friends! On days when we jump for joy,
Hi friends! 悲しくて落ち込める日も
Hi friends! And days when we feel down,
Hi friends! 皆さんの傍でちょこんと
Hi friends! I'll be right by your side
Hi friends! 私がここにいます
Hi friends! I am right here.
そう 今も ずっと
Yes, now and forever
変わらない想いだから
with unchanging feelings,
キミと誰だって推したって Welcome friends!
supporting anyone you like, Welcome friends!
ますます成長中
Growing more and more.
同じ時を過ごす今が幸せなんですよ
The present time we share together is so precious!
泣いたってしょげたって大丈夫じゃい！
Even if you cry or feel down, it's alright!
笑顔で一緒にHi Fine FOX!!
Together with a smile, Hi Fine FOX!!
輝く色を重ねて
Layering shining colors,
広げましょうMy Brand New World
let's spread them out, My Brand New World!
Let's go, my friends! お空を飛び越えて
Let's go, my friends! Flying across the sky,
Let's go, my friends! 世界を回ったら
Let's go, my friends! Traversing the world,
Let's go, my friends! 宇宙の果てまでも
Let's go, my friends! To the edge of the universe,
Let's go, my friends! ココロを通わせよう
Let's go, my friends! Let's connect our hearts.
Welcome, my friends! どこだって届けるよ
Welcome, my friends! I'll reach you anywhere.
Welcome, my friends! いつだって知ってるよ
Welcome, my friends! I always know.
Welcome, my friends! 誰だって繋がるよ
Welcome, my friends! Anyone can connect.
Welcome, my friends! ここから始めよう
Welcome, my friends! Let's start from here.
声を合わせて 一緒にせーの！
Voices together, ready, go!
白上の歌 皆さんに届け〜！
Shirakami's song, reach everyone!
推して推されておにいさんもおねえさんも！
Supporting and being supported, big brothers and big sisters!
ここまでよくできました！
We did so well up to here!
最後にひとつ！3000回でも足りないぞ！100万回愛してる！
Just one last thing! Even 3,000 times isn't enough! I love you a million times!
Love これまでを支えてくれた
Love, supporting me until now,
Love 皆さんに寄り添いたいなって
Love, wanting to stay close to everyone,
Love 大切な仲間達とこれからも
Love, with precious friends from now on,
今もずっと 大好きなこの場所で キミもいつでも推したって
now and forever in this beloved place, supporting you anytime,
キミもいつでも推したって Welcome friends!
supporting you anytime, Welcome friends!
わくわく通信中 まだ見ぬ
Waku-waku communicating, to unseen
明日も未来も お友達ですよ！
tomorrows and futures, we're friends!
泣いたってしょげたって大好きじゃい！
Even if you cry or feel down, I love you!
笑顔で一緒にHi Fine FOX!!
Together with a smile, Hi Fine FOX!!
ココロを歌に重ねて 届けましょうMy Happy Days
Layering our hearts into song, let's deliver them, My Happy Days!
繋げましょうYour Shiny Smile
Let's connect them, Your Shiny Smile!
はい、ということで皆さん！
Hi, everyone!
ついに白上、新しい3Dになりました！わーーい！
Shirakami finally has a new 3D model! Yay!
あ、やばい。ちょっとお水……お水……あ、ここに見えないね、お水があるんです。
Ah, oh no. Some water... water... Ah, you can't see it, but there's water here.
はい、ということで、ええ皆さん！
Yes, so everyone!
ええ、白上新しい3Dになりました！わーーい！
Shirakami has a new 3D model! Yay!
3Dが新しくなりまして、ついに3Dも新しくなりまして！
My 3D has become new, finally my 3D is new too!
ちょっといっぱい色々見てほしいです！おしっぽもボリュームになりましたよ！すごい！
I want you to see lots of things! My tail has become voluminous too! Awesome!
ぼよんぼよんです！ね！お耳もとってもふよふよになりました！
It's bouncy! Right? My ears have become super fluffy too!
ぴこぴこぴこ！
Twitch, twitch, twitch!
じゃあちょっと、あの挨拶ももう一回この新しいモデルでやときますか。
Let's do that greeting again with this new model.
ちょっと恥ずかしいですが。
Even though it's a bit embarrassing.
皆さんこんコンキツネー！ふわふわしっぽのゴムボール、あなたの心の一番星、白上です！
Everyone, Kon-kon Kitsune! The fluffy-tailed rubber ball, your heart's number one star, Shirakami!
はいフレンズ！みたいなー！
Hi friends! Something like that!
わーみんなコメントわー可愛い、ありがとうございます！
Wow, everyone's comments, cute, thank you very much!
今回ですね、ちょっと新衣装をいれてみました！
This time, I added a new outfit!
新しいモデルになるってこと皆さん知らなかったでしょ？
You guys didn't know I'd become a completely new model, did you?
告知しなかったからね！言わなかったのね！ものすごいびっくりしてくれたと思います！
Because I didn't announce it! I didn't say anything! I'm sure you were super surprised!
白上の誕生日だけどみんなへのサプライズプレゼント！いえーい！大成功！
A surprise present to everyone for Shirakami's birthday! Yay! Huge success!
これからね、もっと今日はいっぱい歌おうと思っているのに、もうバテてしまう。
From now on, even though I planned to sing a lot more today, I'm already getting exhausted.
ちなみに今回のライブの選んだ楽曲なんですが、サブタイトルがレトロということで、
By the way, the songs chosen for this live stream have the subtitle "Retro",
白上の気持ちを込めたような楽曲を選曲させていただきました！みんなに伝えたい思いとかも！
so I selected songs that incorporate Shirakami's feelings and thoughts I want to convey!
では、早速白上がバテ果てる前に次の曲いきたいと思います！
Now, before Shirakami gets completely exhausted, let's go to the next song!
次は3曲連続！
Next is 3 songs in a row!
1曲目はコンコンビーツ！みんなちゃんと手振り覚えてくれてますか？
The 1st song is KONKON Beats! Do you all remember the hand gestures?
2曲目はデコニーナさんのスクランブル交差点という曲です！
The 2nd song is "Scramble Crossing" by Dekonina!
白上のこういうところをみんなに知ってほしいなという歌詞や、気持ちの変化を歌っています。
It sings about feelings and wanting everyone to know this side of Shirakami.
3曲目は秘密だけどきっと聴いたことある曲だと思うので、最後まで楽しんでください！
The 3rd song is a secret, but you've probably heard it before, so please enjoy!
ではではまず1曲目、コンコンビーツ聴いてください！
Now then, first song, please listen to KONKON Beats!
Everything's gonna be alrightって感じよ
Everything's gonna be alright, I feel like
今、噂のbewitch you
Now, bewitch you with rumors
沈む太陽におはようって言ったり
Saying good morning to the setting sun
真昼の月におやすみって言ったり
Saying good night to the midday moon
いつだって僕らはちょっとズレてる
Every time we're a bit off
丸い地球のせいかもね
It might be the fault of the round earth
人間事みたいじゃん…だって狐だし
Like human affairs... since I'm a fox
そこんとこよろしくね
Take care of that part
世界中が輪！ってそれ無理じゃない？ってことも
The whole world in a ring! Isn't that impossible?
今からホントになる
It will really happen from now on
Are you ready?
コンコンコン Yes こんな狐に化かされて
Kon kon kon, yes, fooled by such a fox
Knock, knock, knock 心を開けて
Knock, knock, knock, open your heart
Everything's gonna be alrightって感じよ
Everything's gonna be alright, I feel like
今、噂のbewitch you
Now, bewitch you with rumors
やなことがあった日でも
Even on days with bad things happening
笑えちゃう僕らがいいね
It's great when we can laugh
そうだ、君がfriendなら無敵じゃない？ってことよ
That's right, if you're a friend, aren't we invincible?
今でも本気にしてる
I'm serious about it even now
生まれも育ちも話す言葉も
Birth, growth, words spoken
趣味も歩幅も人の愛し方も
Hobbies, pace, ways of loving others
いつだって僕らはちょっとズレてる
Every time we're a bit off
それを大事にしてよ
Cherish that, okay?
こんな狐にバカされて 心を開いて
Being fooled by a fox like this, open your heart!
Everything's gonna be alrightって感じよ
Feeling like "Everything's gonna be alright."
今はウワサのBewitch you もう一回
Right now, I'll bewitch you once again!
こんな狐にバカされて 心を開いて
Being fooled by a fox like this, open your heart!
Don't stop music! ほら朝まで行くよ 今 地球の裏にチューニング
Don't stop music! Come on, till morning, tuning to the earth's other side!
魔法をかけて 飽きるまで Be with you
Cast a spell and be with you until we're sick of it!
スクランブル交際
[Song: Scramble Kousai]
勿体無いじゃない バイバイはないわ もっとスクランブル
Isn't it a waste? No saying bye-bye, let's scramble more!
結構無理じゃない？ 無い愛数えて ちょっと苦しくなる
Isn't it pretty impossible? Counting non-existent love starts to hurt.
全然笑えないNight 内緒話ずっと聞きたくなる
A totally unfunny night, I want to keep hearing secrets.
絶対有り得ない＝大体有り得る きっと僕らリアル
Absolutely impossible = mostly possible, surely we are real.
もうこんなんなってどうしてくれんの なら試しに嫌ってみる？
What'll you do now that it's come to this? Want to try hating me?
バカになってどうぞ まともな中毒性 今はインスタントラブがしたい したいよ
Go ahead and act like a fool, with proper addiction. Now I want instant love!
「好きになって順序踏んで」なんてねどうせ 愛に囚われたまま 傷付け合ってサヨナラすんじゃん
"Fall in love step by step," yeah right. Trapped in love, we hurt each other and say bye.
それならいっそ 歪んだ方が正解じゃん 今も消えないほど痛い 痛いの
Wouldn't it be more correct to be twisted instead? It hurts so much it won't fade.
壊れるほどに求めた正性 次も誰かのために 欲隠して愛を突くんだ
The righteousness we sought until it broke. Once more for someone's sake, we pierce love.
じっとしてって言っといたじゃん
I told you to stay still, didn't I?
勿体無いじゃない バイバイはないわ もっとスクランブル
Isn't it a waste? No saying bye-bye, let's scramble more!
結構無理じゃない？ 無い愛数えて ちょっと苦しくなる
Isn't it pretty impossible? Counting non-existent love starts to hurt.
へえ、まあまあいいじゃんか 四つ打つ出会いの衝動 もっともっとちょうだい
Well, pretty decent isn't it? Four-on-the-floor impulse, give me more!
へえ、まあまあいいじゃんか 裏打つ別れの衝動 もっともっとちょうだい ねぇもっともっとちょうだい
Well, pretty decent isn't it? Off-beat impulse, give me more and more!
妄想なんとかって歌いたい 曖昧こそ好きってなる
I want to sing about some delusion, ambiguity makes me love it.
バカになってどうぞ まともな中毒性 今はインスタントラブがしたい したいよ
Go ahead and act like a fool, with proper addiction. Now I want instant love!
「好きになって順序踏んで」なんてねどうせ 愛に囚われたまま 傷付け合ってサヨナラすんじゃん
"Fall in love step by step," yeah right. Trapped in love, we hurt each other and say bye.
それならいっそ 歪んだ方が正解じゃん 今も消えないほど痛い 痛いの
Wouldn't it be more correct to be twisted instead? It hurts so much it won't fade.
壊れるほどに求めた正性 次も誰かのために 欲隠して愛を突くんだ
The righteousness we sought until it broke. Once more for someone's sake, we pierce love.
それでもあなたを愛したことだけが 消えてくれやしない しないよ
Even so, only the fact that I loved you will never fade away, no it won't!
いつになって誰を愛したとて 僕の中で進化するんだ 息をするんだ
No matter when or who I loved, it evolves inside my heart, it breathes!
じっとしてって言っといたじゃん
I told you to stay still, didn't I?
弾けて もっと 甘く 熟して
Pop, get even sweeter and ripen up!
どこまでも あたし を 愛して
Love me all the way anywhere!
弾けて もっと 甘く 熟してね
Pop, get even sweeter and ripen up, hey!
ah chuku chuku cherry cherry bomb!
真っ赤に染まった cherry heart 衝撃的なほどに初んな
A cherry heart dyed bright red, innocent to a shocking degree.
いわゆる初恋みたいな恋
A love like so-called first love.
いわゆる 初恋 みたいな恋
It's like a so-called first love.
どうにかなっちゃうよ チェリーハート
It's driving me crazy, cherry heart!
爆発的威力で君は あたしを虜にしたの
With explosive power, you made me your captive.
キュンとなっちゃうでしょ
It makes my heart go throb, right?
突っかかれすぎて
Being rushed too much...
もっともっと真っ赤になっちゃうの
I'm turning more and more bright red!
弾けて もっと甘く熟して
Bursting, ripening even sweeter,
どこまでもあたしを愛して
love me no matter where!
チェリー チェリーボム
Cherry cherry bomb!
弾けて もっと甘く熟してねぇ
Bursting, ripening even sweeter, hey!
あちゅくちゅく チェリー チェリーボム
Achuku chuku, cherry cherry bomb!
チェリー チェリーボム
Cherry cherry bomb!
とろとろとろとろとろけちゃう
Melting away completely,
あたしの一番弱いとこ
my most vulnerable spot.
もうどうになっちゃいそうよ チェリーハート
It's driving me out of my mind, cherry heart!
そわそわそわそわそわしちゃう
Fidgeting and feeling restless,
あなたの一番弱いとこ どうにかしてあげるわ
I'll do something about your most vulnerable spot!
キュンとなっちゃうでしょ
It makes your heart go throb, right?
突っかかれすぎて
Being rushed too much...
もっともっと真っ赤になっちゃうの
I'm turning more and more bright red!
弾けて もっと甘く熟して
Bursting, ripening even sweeter,
絶対的にあたしを愛して
absolutely love me!
チェリー チェリーボム
Cherry cherry bomb!
弾けて もっと甘く熟してねぇ
Bursting, ripening even sweeter, hey!
あちゅくちゅく チェリー チェリーボム
Achuku chuku, cherry cherry bomb!
チェリー チェリーボム
Cherry cherry bomb!
男の子も
Boys too...
女の子も
Girls too...
男の子も
Boys too...
女の子も
Girls too...
男の子も
Boys too...
女の子も
Girls too...
いやだめ ノーノーノーノー！
No way, stop, no no no no!
弾けて もっと甘く熟して
Bursting, ripening even sweeter,
どこまでもあたしを愛して
love me no matter where!
チェリー チェリーボム
Cherry cherry bomb!
弾けて もっと甘く熟してねぇ あちゅくちゅく
Bursting, ripening even sweeter, hey, achuku chuku!
チェリー チェリーボム 弾けて もっと甘く熟して
Cherry cherry bomb, bursting, ripening even sweeter,
絶対的にあたしを愛して 弾けて もっと甘く熟してねぇ
absolutely love me, bursting, ripening even sweeter, hey!
あちゅくちゅくちゅくちゅく…
Achuku chuku chuku chuku...
チェリー チェリーボム
Cherry cherry bomb!
はい、ということでチェリーボムでした！ありがとうございましたー！
Hi, so that was Cherry Bomb! Thank you very much!
いやー、ギター重いですね。よいしょっと。
Man, guitars are heavy. Heave-ho.
はい、今回はこちらのブライト衣装でやってみました！いえーい！二着目もありがと、うう、ありがと！
Yep, this time we did it with this bright outfit! Yay! Thanks for the second outfit too!
はい、いやもうチェリーボムね、本当に大好きな曲で、前にね祭ちゃんとあの、サイサイの楽曲を歌ったことがあるんですけど、今回はソロでのチェリーボムでした！
Yeah, I really love Cherry Bomb, and I sang Saisi's song with Matsuri-chan before, but this time it was a solo Cherry Bomb!
この歌詞もですね、あの、すごいあのね、キュンとするような歌詞になってて、なんかね、なんか白髪の気持ちとかも入ってるような、本当に素敵な歌となっております。
And the lyrics are super heart-throbbing, and it feels like it includes Shirakami's feelings too, it's a truly wonderful song.
ぜひ原曲も聴いてみてくださいねー！
Please be sure to listen to the original song too!
あのー、好きなとこ、好きなところと言いますか、歌ってすごいよかったなって思ったところなんですけど、「いや、だめ、のーのーのーのー」がちょっとね、可愛く歌えてよかったかなと思います。
As for my favorite parts, singing it was so great, but "No way, stop, no no no no" was cute and I'm glad I could sing it well.
さてさてさて、じゃあちょっと次の曲もありますので、ではここで一旦次の楽曲用の衣装に前日していきましょうか！
Now then, since we have the next song, let's head to the outfit for the next song!
はい、ということで次はお水着でございます！
Alright, so next up is the swimsuit!
この新しい白上での水着のお披露目は今日が初ですね！ね、もう寒くなってきてる
Today is the first reveal of this new Shirakami swimsuit! Right, it's getting cold...
ちょっと歌いますか、ちょっと夏らしい曲を歌おうかなと思います。
I'm going to sing a somewhat summery song,
ふーっしょ、ちょっとねギターを持った腕がちょっと痛いですけども、このまま頑張って
holding the guitar makes my arm a bit sore, but I'll do my best
歌いたいと思います。それでは聞いてください、「青と夏」。
to sing it. So please listen: "Ao to Natsu".
涼しい風吹く
A cool wind blows
青空の匂い
The scent of the blue sky
今日はダラッと少し過ごしてみようか
Let's spend today taking it easy
風鈴がチリン
The clinking of wind chimes
ひまわりの黄色
The yellow of sunflowers
私には関係ないと 思ってたんだ
I thought it had nothing to do with me
夏が始まった
Summer has begun
合図がした
The signal has been given
傷つき疲れるけどもいいんだ
It hurts and tires me out, but that's okay
次の恋の行方はどこだ
Where will the next love lead?
映画じゃない
It's not a movie
主役は誰だ
Who is the protagonist?
映画じゃない
It's not a movie
僕らの番だ
It's our turn
優しい風吹く
A gentle wind blows
夕焼けの「またね」
Goodbye to the sunset
わかっているけどいつか終わる
I know it will end someday
風鈴がチリン
The clinking of wind chimes
スイカの種飛ばし
Throwing watermelon seeds
私にも関係あるかもね
It might have something to do with me too
友達の嘘も
Friends' lies
転がされる愛も
Love that rolls around
何から信じていいんでしょうね
What should I believe in?
大人になってもしきっと 宝物は褪せないよ
Even when we become adults, treasures won't fade
大丈夫だから今はさ 青に飛び込んでいよう
It's okay, so let's jump into the blue now
夏が始まった
Summer has begun
恋に落ちた
Fell in love
もう待ち疲れたんだけど、どうですか？？
I'm tired of waiting, how about you??
本気になればなるほど辛い
The more serious it gets, the harder it is
平和じゃない 私の恋だ
It's not peaceful, it's my love
私の恋だ
It's my love
寂しいな やっぱり寂しいな
Lonely, I'm lonely after all
いつか忘れられてしまうんだろうか
Will I eventually be forgotten?
それでもね 「繋がり」求める
Even so, seeking connections
人の素晴らしさを信じてる
I believe in the greatness of people
運命が突き動かされてゆく
Fate is pushing us forward
赤い糸が音を立てる
The red thread makes a sound
主役はあなただ
You are the protagonist
夏が始まった
Summer has begun
君はどうだ
How about you?
素直になれる勇気はあるか
Do you have the courage to be honest?
この恋の行方はどこだ
Where will this love lead?
映画じゃない
It's not a movie
愛しい日々だ
Lovely days
恋が始まった
Love has begun
合図がした
The signal has been given
今日を待ちわびたなんて良い日だ
Today is a good day we've been waiting for
まだまだ終われないこの夏は
This summer is not over yet
映画じゃない
It's not a movie
君らの番だ
It's your turn
映画じゃない
It's not a movie
僕らの青だ
It's our blue
映画じゃない 僕らの夏だ
It's not a movie, it's our summer
はーい、ということで
So, with that being said,
アート夏でしたー！ありがとうございます！
it was Art Summer! Thank you very much!
いやもうこの曲ね、背景はものすごく、あの、スポーティな感じだったんですけど
Well, this song, the background was very, um, sporty-looking,
白上は、あの、夏といえば水着ということでね、
and for Shirakami, since summer means swimsuits,
水着のお披露目も兼ねて踊っていただきました。
I wore one for its debut!
いやこの曲もなんかこう自分たちの胸に訴えかけてくるような曲でねえ。
This song also reaches out and appeals right to our hearts, you know.
いやもう白上もこの夏、皆さんの中では主役に慣れたんじゃないかなと思うぐらいね、あのいっぱい楽しんだのでね、はい。
I enjoyed this summer so much I feel like I became the main character to everyone, so yeah.
ちょっと恥ずかしいですな。恥ずかしいですね、改めて水着。
That's a bit embarrassing. Seeing the swimsuit again is embarrassing.
はい、ではですね、えーと、汗もちょっとやばいですけども
Right, well then, um, I'm sweating pretty intensely though,
えー、次の曲いきましょう。
um, let's go to the next song.
次の曲はちょっと、皆さんに近い真ん中のホールで歌っちゃおうかなと思います。
I think I'll sing the next song in the middle hall close to everyone.
次の曲はですね、なんと、皆さん、ついにこのステージで歌うことができます！
And amazingly, everyone, you can finally hear it on this stage!
FUNKY MONKEY BABYSさんの「希望の唄」！
FUNKY MONKEY BABYS's "Kibou no Uta"!
歌枠のときもいつかステージで歌いたいなって言ってたのをすっごい覚えてくれてますかー？
Do you remember me saying during singing streams that I wanted to sing it on stage someday?
ね、歌わせていただこうかと思います。
Right, I thought I'd sing it.
おっと、一口お水飲んでからステージ行きますね。
Whoops, let's drink a sip of water before heading to the stage.
では、希望の唄、聞いてください。
Well then, please listen to "Kibou no Uta".
あなたがいて
With you here...
あなたといて
being here with you...
もしもこの世にあなたが 存在していなかったら 100ある笑顔のうち 少しだけでも40はなくなる
If you didn't exist in this world, out of 100 smiles, at least 40 would disappear.
もしも地球の裏側 あなたがいると分かったら 無くなった40の笑顔 取り戻すため海を渡ろう
If I learned you were on the other side of the world, I'd cross the ocean to get those 40 lost smiles back.
あなたの涙が雨になる
Your tears become the rain,
あなたの言葉が風になる
your words become the wind.
諦めかけて乾いた心に 希望という花が咲いた
In this dried heart that was ready to give up, a flower called hope has bloomed.
ああ 気付いてほしい
Ah, I want you to realize...
この歌の意味を知ってほしい
I want you to know the meaning of this song.
僕にとってこんなにも 大事です必要な人
You are so precious and necessary to me.
あなたがいて あなたといて こんなに幸せになるよ
With you here, being here with you, I can be this happy!
忘れないで そのぬくもり 他の誰でもないあなた
Don't forget that warmth, you are not anyone else.
あの涙も その笑顔も あの涙も その笑顔も
Those tears, that smile, those tears, that smile...
この無数にある出会いの中 偶然あなたと繋がった
Among all these countless meetings, by some chance I connected with you.
もしも出会えなかったなら 夢すら持ててなかった
If I had never met you, I wouldn't have even been able to dream.
いつの間にかあなたの笑顔が 変わらない本当の居場所
At some point your smile became my one true, unchanging place to belong.
心から支えられている だから僕は笑っていられる
You support me from the heart, and that's why I can smile.
ともに遠回りとかもしたけど 辿ってきた夢の足跡
We took the long way around at times, but these are the footprints of the dream we've reached.
昔から変わらず今でも たくさんの勇気をありがとう
Unchanging from long ago even now, thank you for so much courage.
振り返らずにまた前へと これからも重ねて行く年
Never looking back, moving forward again, the years we'll keep adding on.
僕には歌しかないけれど ずっと見守って欲しい
All I have is my song, but I want you to watch over me always.
あなたがいて あなたといて こんなに幸せになるよ
With you here, being here with you, I can be this happy!
忘れないで そのぬくもり 他の誰でもないあなた
Don't forget that warmth, you are not anyone else.
この世界で 一人だけの あなたに出会えた奇跡が こんな僕を 勇気付ける 力があなたにはあるの
The miracle of meeting the one and only you in this world gives courage to someone like me—you have that power!
いつも愛してくれた人よ 僕に今何が出来るなら
To the one who has always loved me, if there is something I can do for you now,
探していた 未来の灯を
searching for the light of the future,
あなたと 分かち合いたい
I want to share it with you.
あなたがいて あなたといて こんなに幸せになるよ
With you here, being here with you, I can be this happy!
忘れないで そのぬくもり 他の誰でもないあなた
Don't forget that warmth, you are not anyone else.
あなたがいて あなたがいて こんなに幸せになるよ
With you here, with you here, I'm so happy.
この世界で 一人だけの あなたに出会えた奇跡が
The miracle of meeting the only you in this world...
こんな僕を 勇気づける 力があなたにはあるの
...has the power to encourage someone like me. You have that power.
ありがとう 見つけてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for finding me, thank you.
受け止めてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for accepting me.
愛してくれて ありがとう
Thank you for loving me.
ありがとう 覚えててくれて ありがとう
Thank you for remembering me, thank you.
受け入れてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for welcoming me.
大切にしてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for cherishing me.
“あなたに出会えてよかった”なんて
Saying "I'm so glad I met you,"
どうでもいいほど 当たり前でさ
is so obvious it almost goes without saying,
だけどね 言わなきゃね 死んじゃうから僕らは
but still, we have to say it, or else we'd perish.
ありがとうね 愛してる
Thank you, I love you.
この声も
Even this voice,
この顔も
even this face,
この夢も
even this dream,
この日々も
even these days,
この過去も
even this past,
この道も
even this path,
悲しさも
even the sadness...
ひとりじゃ ひとりじゃ
is not alone, not alone.
この歌も
Even this song,
この夜も
even this night,
この愛も
even this love,
戸惑いも
even the bewilderment...
これからも あなたがいて
From now on too, with you here
僕がいて
and me here,
意味を持つ
it all has meaning.
ありがとう 分け合ってくれて ありがとう
Thank you for sharing it with me, thank you.
約束をくれて ありがとう
Thank you for making promises with me.
虚しさをくれて ありがとう
Thank you for giving me emptiness.
ありがとう 理屈など超えて ありがとう
Thank you, going beyond reason, thank you.
極論をくれて ありがとう
Thank you for giving me extremes.
大切をくれて ありがとう
Thank you for giving me what's precious.
この声も
Even this voice,
この顔も
even this face,
この夢も
even this dream,
この日々も
even these days,
この過去も
even this past,
この道も 喜びも
even this path, even the joy...
ひとりじゃ ひとりじゃ
is not alone, not alone.
この歌も
Even this song,
この夜も
even this night,
この愛も 戸惑いも
even this love, even the bewilderment...
これからも あなたがいて
From now on too, with you here
僕がいて
and me here,
生きていく
we will live on.
何度も何度も “ありがとう”を
Saying "Thank you" over and over again...
忘れて 忘れて 見失って
Forgetting, forgetting, losing sight...
失して 悔やんで また気付いて
Losing, regretting, and realizing once again...
何度もあなたを 思い出して
remembering you time and time again.
変わっていく生活 重ねる歳
Changing lives, growing older.
変わっていく自分と 変わる今と
The changing self, the changing present.
それでも あの日と同じ距離の 声の 愛の
Yet, at the same distance as that day, with that voice, with that love...
あなたがいること わかったよ
I realized that you are here.
ありがとう ありがとう
Thank you, thank you.
あなたの願いと 祈りと 迷いと
Your wishes, prayers, hesitations,
孤独と 夢と 明日と
loneliness, dreams, tomorrow,
僕も共に生きるよ あなたがその想いをくれたんだよ
I'll live alongside them too, because you gave me those feelings.
「あなたに会えてよかった」なんて
Saying "I'm so glad I met you"
どうでもいいほど 当たり前でさ
is so obvious it doesn't even need to be said,
だけどね 言わなきゃね 死んじゃうから僕らは
but still, we have to say it, or we'll perish,
ありがとうね あいしてる
Thank you, I love you.
ありがとう
Thank you.
ライブの途中ですが、じゃーん！
We're in the middle of the live, but tada!
グッズ紹介担当のホワイトフブニャんだにゃん！
It's me, White Fubunya, in charge of goods introductions!
韓国から収録とか意味わかんないけど、まあ、しごできなところ見せちゃおっかな！
Recording from Korea makes no sense, but whatever, I'll show you how competent I am!
緊張しすぎてMCで喋ることほぼ喋れてない、かわいいそうなフブニャに変わってお知らせです！
Since I'm too nervous to say almost anything in my MC, I'm taking over as the pitiful Fubunya to make an announcement!
今年もございます！2023年誕生日記念グッズ！フブニャのためにいっぱい買ってね！
It's here again this year! 2023 Birthday Commemorative Goods! Buy lots for Fubunya!
まずはこちら！みんなでだらだらアクリルジオラスタンド！
First up! Everyone's Relaxing Acrylic Diorama Stand!
イラストはリいちゅさんが担当してくれました！
The illustration was done by Riichu-san!
こういうジオラマって、キャラクターと背景の間にポストカードとかチェキとか挟んで立てかけられたり、インテリアとしても使えるんじゃないかな？
With a diorama like this, can't you sandwich postcards or chekis between the character and background and display it, or use it as interior decor?
あれれ、もしかしてフブニャ天才じゃん！
Wait, could Fubunya be a genius?!
新小のお部屋スタイルでだらだらなデザインとなってます！
It's designed with the Shinsho room style for a relaxed look!
続いては、バックステージパスケース！
Next is the backstage pass case!
ライブをお手伝いしてくれるスタッフすこん部君になれちゃうぞい！
You can become Staff Sukonbu-kun who helps out at the live!
イベントなので名刺として使うもよし、お仕事なのでも使える人は使ってね！
Since it's an event, it's great for business cards, or if you can use it for work, go ahead!
フブニャも担当君にプレゼントしちゃおうかな？
Should I gift one to Tanto-kun too?
名前はもちろんフブニャのに付ける！
Of course, I'll name it Fubunya's!
すこん部君のお耳の再現もすごいね！
Sukonbu-kun's ears recreation is amazing too!
裏面はなんか、前にフブニャがみんなと話し合ってこういうのいいねっていうのを取り入れたんだって！
The back apparently incorporates an idea Fubunya discussed with everyone before!
しごできじゃん、えらぴっぴ！洋服衣装のスカートにあるデザインがカプセルに入ってるよ！
So competent, good job! The design from the casual outfit skirt is inside the capsule!
続いて、ランダムラバーキーホルダー！イラストはヤナナンさんが担当！
Next, random rubber keychain! Illustrated by Yananan-san!
超絶最高のラバーキーホルダー！構築てぶにゃんこれ大好き！
An ultra-awesome rubber keychain! Kouchiku Tebunyan loves this!
通常衣装、部屋着衣装、洋服衣装にふぶらコスプレのラバーキーホルダー！オタク君のカバンにつけるもよし、さっきのバックステージパスにつけるのもいいかも！
Normal outfit, loungewear outfit, casual outfit, and Fubura cosplay rubber keychain! Great for attaching to an otaku's bag or the backstage pass!
ちなみに汚れたラバーキーホルダーにはジョコ液を綿棒につけてこするといいらしいって聞いたんだけど、ガチ？
By the way, I heard rubbing dirty rubber keychains with kitchen cleanser on a cotton swab works, is that for real?
最後はまさかのフブキの部屋着ジャージ！
Lastly, Fubuki's loungewear jersey!
部屋着フブニャも欲しい！
Loungewear Fubunya wants one too!
男女兼用サイズだから担当君にも着せられちゃうね！
It's unisex size so you can make Tanto-kun wear it too!
普段着使いしやすいシンプルなデザインだし、これまで出したTシャツにも合うんじゃないかな？
It's a simple design easy for everyday wear, and it should match the T-shirts released so far!
オタク君たちのジャージ姿、フブニャも見てみたいよ！
I'd love to see otaku-kun's jersey looks too!
ねぇ、おそろっちにしようよ！
Hey, let's match!
は？ 今やだって言った？
Huh? Did you just say no?
そして今回もございます！数量限定フルセット購入特典直筆サイン入り！
And we also have this! Quantity-limited full set purchase bonus with handwritten signature!
今回は初のチェキ風ブロマイドカード！
This time, it's our first cheki-style bromide card!
ってこれ、願うふにゃふにゃで超絶アイドルのお寝起き顔が激写ってこと？究極の宝じゃん！
Wait, does this mean an ultra-desirable, super-cute idol's just-woken-up face is captured? It's the ultimate treasure!
まあ、フブニャはこういう願うとか絶対見せないけどね！
Well, Fubunya would never show such wishing faces!
以上、今年の誕生日グッズのご紹介でした！引き続きライブをお楽しみになってくださいね！
That concludes the introduction of this year's birthday goods! Please continue enjoying the live!
もうすぐ時計は6時
Soon the clock will strike 6
もうそこに一番星
The first star is already there
影を踏んで 夜に紛れたくなる 帰り道
Stepping on my shadows, on my way home wanting to blend into the night
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I search
どんなに探してみても 一つしかない星
No matter how hard I search, there's only one star.
何億光年 離れたところから
From somewhere billions of light-years away...
あんなに輝く
Shining so brightly,
いいな 君は みんなから愛されて
you're so lucky, loved by everyone.
「いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ」
"Well, I've always been all alone."
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If we gather together and become a constellation...
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
A falling star, a fleeting wish.
きらめいて ゆらめいて 震えてるシグナル
Sparkling, flickering, trembling signals.
空見上げて 指を差されるような
Like pointing up at the sky,
つないだ線 解かないで
never untie this connected line.
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how dazzling I might be...
もうすぐ時計は８時
It's almost 8 o'clock.
夜空に満天の星
The night sky is filled with stars.
何億光年 離れたところにはもうないかもしれない
That distant place might no longer exist.
月が綺麗で 泣きそうになるのは
The moon is so pretty, it makes me want to cry.
いつの日か 別れが来るから
Because one day, a parting will come.
君と集まって 星座になれたら
If we gather together and become a constellation...
流星みたい 流れるひとりごと
A monologue flowing like a meteor.
消えていく 残像は 真夜中のプリズム
The fading afterimage is a midnight prism.
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If our earnest wishes reach someone...
変わるかな 夜の淵をなぞるような こんな僕でも
Can I change, tracing the abyss of the night, even a nobody like me?
遥か彼方 僕らは出会ってしまった
We met far, far away.
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
That's why we'll cross paths again and again.
雲の隙間で
Through the gaps in the clouds.
君と集まって 星座になれたら 夜広げて描こう絵空事を
If we gather together and become a constellation, let's paint an impossible dream across the night.
暗闇を照らすような満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon illuminating the darkness,
だから集まって星座になりたい 色とりどりの光 放ような
That's why I want us to gather and become a constellation, radiating colorful lights.
つないだ線 解かないよ
Never untie this connected line,
君がどんなに眩しくても
no matter how dazzling you are.
平穏すぎて くだらない世界
In a mundane and boring world,
閉ざしてた 誰も信じずに
not trusting anyone and keeping it closed,
こじ開けたんだ 君が突然に
you suddenly pried it open.
あのまなざしが僕を救った 初めて触れる感情
That gaze saved me, touching my emotions for the very first time.
消えないように 握りしめて
Holding on tightly so it won't fade away,
繋がる心の声 まだ見ぬ世界へと
headed toward a yet-unseen world on the voice of our connected hearts.
瞳に映っている 眩しすぎる今が 嘘だとしても構わない
Reflected in my eyes, even if the dazzling present is a lie, I don't care.
響き続けた声を追って いつしかここが居場所になって
Chasing the voice that kept echoing, finding a place where this finally belongs.
平穏すぎて くだらない世界
A world too peaceful and mundane,
(全てが)
(everything)
閉ざしてた 誰も信じずに
I had closed off, trusting no one,
こじ開けたんだ 君が突然に
Until you suddenly forced it open
(手を引く)
(taking my hand).
あの眼差しが 僕を救った
That gaze of yours saved me.
初めて触れる感情
Emotions I felt for the very first time
(あふれる)
(overflowing)
消えないように
So they wouldn't fade away,
握りしめて
I held them tight.
繋ぐ 心の声
Connecting voices of the heart
(ここにいるよ)
("I'm right here"),
まだ見ぬ世界へと
Toward a world yet unseen
(導く)
(guiding me).
瞳に映っている 眩しすぎる今が
The present reflected in my eyes is so dazzling,
嘘でも構わない
Even if it's a lie, I don't care
(幻でも)
(even if it's an illusion).
揺れる 心の声
A swaying voice of the heart,
溢れ出す 想いも
and overflowing feelings—
時が過ぎるだけで 忘れてゆくなんて
that they would simply be forgotten as time passes...
どうしても悔しくて
I couldn't help but feel frustrated by it.
深い 僕の心まで (届いている)
Deep into my heart (it reaches)
名前を呼ぶ声が (聞こえる)
The voice calling my name (I can hear it).
いつまでも続くなんて あり得ないとわかっていたけど
Even though I knew it could never last forever
(一瞬だって)
(even for just a moment)
遠ざかる 景色の中
Amidst the receding scenery,
また夢を見ていた
I was dreaming once again.
はーい、ということで「ブルージャーニー」より歌方をお聞きいただきました。ありがとうございます！
Alright! So that was "Utakata" from Blue Journey. Thank you very much!
そして「ブルージャーニー」以上でございまーす！
And that concludes the Blue Journey portion!
いやもう本当にこの衣装、めちゃめちゃ可愛いので、こうやってちゃんと新しいお召し姿でのお披露目もできて嬉しいです！
Man, this outfit is seriously super cute, so I'm so happy I could debut it in this brand new look!
ってさっきブルー・ジャーニーの楽曲もね、ライブをね見に来てくれた方だとね、ふと二人足りないんじゃないかなと思うんですけども
And you know, for those of you who came to see the Blue Journey live, you might be thinking, "Aren't two people missing?"
実は この曲「あの日は、何度…」「あの日の君へ」とルミネと3人で歌っておりますので、あのまだね、あの歌方結局聴いてないよって方は是非とも聴いていただけると嬉しいです！
Actually, we sang this song—along with "Ano Hi wa Nando..." and "Ano Hi no Kimi e"—with the three of us at Lumine. So if you haven't listened to Utakata yet, I'd really love for you to check it out!
さてさて、まあね、こちらの楽曲、まあ結構ね切ない感じの楽曲 なんですけども、
Now, as for this song, well, it's a pretty bittersweet kind of song,
まあなんかそういう気持ちの時もみんなあるよねみたいな、えー曲でちょっとしんみりしつつも、また夢を見ていたというね夢オチとなんとも言えない悲しいような寂しいような曲となっておりました が、
but you know, we all have times when we feel that way, right? It's a song that's a bit somber, yet has that "it was all a dream" kind of ending—a rather sad and lonely sort of track.
皆さんの心にちょっとでも響いてくれたらいいなと思い選曲しました！
But I chose it hoping it would resonate even just a little bit in everyone's hearts!
さて、ついに次で最後の曲でーす！ 最後の曲はなんと白上フブキオリジナル楽曲となっております、新曲です！
And now, finally, it's the last song! And the final song is none other than Shirakami Fubuki's original song—a brand new track!
こちらの楽曲歌ったあとはもうねすぐバイバイになってしまうので、ちょっとこの楽曲は、まあね結構白上織曲では白上からみんなに伝えたいみたいな感じだったんですけども
After singing this song, we'll be saying goodbye right away, so... while this song—well, in my previous original songs, it felt like I wanted to convey something from myself to everyone,
今回の新曲は、結構ファム目線の楽曲となっておりますので、なんかみんなもこういう気持ちでだったらいいなとか、白上はなんかこういう気持ちで推しのこと見てるよっていう、
but this new song is written very much from the fan's perspective. So I hope everyone can feel this way too, or feel like, "This is the feeling with which I'm watching my oshi."
カスタとなっておりますので、なんか共感していっぱい歌ってくれたらいいなと思っております！
It's customized that way, so I hope you can resonate with it and sing along a lot!
では、いきますかね？ じゃあ最後の楽曲白上フブキオリジナル楽曲聞いてください。「レター」
Well, shall we go? Alright, please listen to the final track, Shirakami Fubuki's original song: "Letter."
Dear My Fave, 「ありがとう」を込めて
Dear My Fave, with "Thank you" poured inside,
キミの名は かけがえのない光
Your name is an irreplaceable light.
リアルだって 頑張れる！
Even in reality, I can do my best!
だって、言葉ひとつで胸が躍る
Because a single word makes my heart leap.
“限界”と呼ばれたっていい
It's fine if they call it my "limit,"
生きる理由なんです
It's the reason I live.
へこんだって 見失ったって
Even if I feel down, even if I lose sight,
また私を照らしてくれる
You'll light me up once again.
心臓はしずかみされて 気絶しちゃいそうです
My heart is gripped so tightly I feel like I might faint.
一生懸命な姿に 何度も勇気をもらったから
Because your earnest figure gave me courage time and time again,
今度は私がエールになりたい
Now I want to be the one cheering for you.
I want to be the one to cheer you on this time.
挑め 全熱量の讃歌
Take on this anthem of total passion!
Dear my fave,
「大好き！」が溢れた
"I love you!" overflows from my heart.
この想い、手紙に書いて贈ります
I'll write these feelings in a letter and send them to you.
you made my day
夢を叶えて
making my dreams come true.
君の笑顔が、私の原動力
Your smile is my energy—
you will always be the first star in my heart☆彡
どこまでもついてゆくよ！
I'll follow you anywhere!
I'm your biggest fan
「幸せ」って 君と出会って過ごす日々だと
"Happiness" is defined as the days spent meeting you—
定義された！
yes, it's defined!
会えない時間だって…良い！
Even time apart is... fine!
愛を育てるんです
We're just nurturing our love.
どうしたって叫びたくなった
No matter what, I wanted to shout it out—
イタズラが重の重の重っっ！！
this mischievous, overwhelming love!
来世も来来世までも
For lives and lives to come,
語り継ぎたいのです
I want to pass this story on.
一瞬一瞬が
Every single moment makes
ときめくよ
my heart flutter so.
両手に一杯の
With memories filling
思い出
both my hands.
確かめ合えば寂しくないから
If we confirm it together, we won't be lonely,
繋げ全絆の結晶
so connect this crystal of all our bonds!
dear my fave,
「がんばって！」なんて言えない
I can't just say "Do your best!"
「大丈夫」の三文字で伝わるかな…
I wonder if the three letters of "It's okay" will convey it...
day by day
そう、君のおかげで
yeah, thanks to you,
少しだけ、自分を好きになれたから
I've grown to like myself just a little bit more.
君らしく keep smiling and enjoy yourself
Be yourself, keep smiling and enjoy yourself!
心から願う 私がいる
I'm here, wishing from the bottom of my heart—
ひとりじゃない
you're not alone!
dear my fave,
「大好き！」を集めた
gathering up all my "I love yous!"
愛言葉 手紙に書いて贈ります
I'll write these words of love in a letter and send them.
you made my life
夢で終わらない
and it won't end as a dream.
君だけが、君こそが起こす奇跡
You alone, yes, you are the one who creates miracles.
you will always be the first star in my heart☆彡
信じて夜空のようにずっと
Believing in it like the night sky forever—
i will follow you forever
ありったけの愛を込めて 「ありがとう」
With all the love I have: "Thank you."
君というたった一つの奇跡
To you, my one and only miracle.
銀河を越えて掛け合うフレーズ 輝かせて
Let our echoing phrases shine across the galaxy!
Best wishes,